A Guide to the Rockefeller Brothers Fund records, Board of Trustees, RG 1, Series 1 FA386
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Brothers Fund records, Board of Trustees, RG 1, Series 1
1940-1997
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Brothers Fund
FA386
20 microform reels
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection has been donated to the Rockefeller Archive Center by RBF.
File Plan
Former Classification: V
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Consists of meeting meetings, officers actions, documents of record, by-laws, and other associated vital records of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund.
Arrangement
Primarily chronological.
- Board of Trustees, 1940-1997; 1; 20 microform reels
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains Rockefeller Brothers Fund Minutes, 1940-1996; Certificate of Incorporation and By-laws, 1940-1992 (as amended); and Documents of Record, 1940-1997, Volume 1 – Volume 74.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  The material has been reformatted. The original records have been returned to the Rockefeller Brothers Fund. User copies of the microfilm are available for scholarly access.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  The minutes and documents of record were received by Rockefeller Archive Center in 1998 and temporarily accessioned as 1998:034. Following microfilming, the original records were returned to the Rockefeller Brothers Fund.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Records twenty years old or older are open for scholarly research.
  Arrangement
  The records are arranged into two subseries: 1. Minutes and vital records. 2. Documents of Record.
  Each subseries is arranged chronologically.
  - Minutes and Vital records, 1940-1996; 1.1
    - 1940-1948 (Reel 1)
    - 1949-1952 (Reel 1)
    - 1953-1956 (Reel 1)
    - 1957-1960 (Reel 1)
    - 1961-1963 (Reel 1)
    - 1964-1966 (Reel 2)
    - 1967-1969 (Reel 2)
    - 1970-1971 (Reel 2)
    - 1972-1973 (Reel 2)
    - 1974-1975 (Reel 2)
    - 1976-1977 (Reel 3)
    - 1978-1979 (Reel 3)
    - 1980-1981 (Reel 3)
    - 1982-1984 (Reel 3)
    - 1985-1987 (Reel 3)
    - 1988-1990 (Reel 4)
    - 1991-1992 (Reel 4)
    - 1993-1994 (Reel 4)
    - 1995-1996 (Reel 4)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, 1940 December 23 (Reel 4)
    - Certificate of Change of Provisions and Change of Number of Directors, 1958 October 14 (Reel 4)
    - Certificate of Change of Number of Directors, 1968 June 11 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, 1940 December 23 (amended: 1952; 1954; 1958; 1961) (Reel 4)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, as amended, 1958 October 16 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1961 May 18 (Reel 4)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, as amended, 1968 July 22 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1968 November 21 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1970 May 21 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1970 November 19 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1972 June 26 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1972 November 16 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1973 May 23 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1975 November 20 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1977 June 16 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1979 June 21 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1981 December 2 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1984 June 26 (Reel 4)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, as amended, 1984 October 31 (Reel 4)
    - Composite Certificate of Incorporation, as amended, 1989 June 27 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1990 June 14 (Reel 4)
    - By-Laws, as amended, 1992 April 7 (Reel 4)
  - Documents of Record, 1940-1997; 1.2
    - Volume 1 (1-100), 1940-1947 (Reel 5)
    - Volume 2 (101-204), 1948-1950 (Reel 5)
    - Volume 3 (205-331), 1951-1953 (Reel 5)
    - Volume 4 (332-426), 1954-1955 (Reel 5)
    - Volume 5 (427-518), 1956-1957 (Reel 6)
    - Volume 6 (519-617), 1957-1958 (Reel 6)
    - Volume 7 (618-672), 1959-1960 (Reel 6)
    - Volume 8 (673-736), 1960 (Reel 6)
    - Volume 9 (737-815), 1961 (Reel 6)
    - Volume 10 (816-878), 1962 (Reel 7)
    - Volume 11 (879-951), 1963 (Reel 7)
    - Volume 12 (952-1031), 1964 (Reel 7)
    - Volume 13 (1,032-1,111), 1965 (Reel 7)
    - Volume 14 (1,112-2,004), 1966 (Reel 7)
    - Volume 15 (2,005-2,093), 1967 (Reel 8)
    - Volume 16 (2,094-4,024), 1968-1969 May 6 (Reel 8)
    - Volume 17 (4,025-5,041), 1969 May 6-1970 May 21 (Reel 8)
    - Volume 18 (5,042-6,039), 1970 May 14-December 31 (Reel 8)
    - Volume 19 (6,040-6,094), 1971 January 18-1971 May 20 (Reel 8)
    - Volume 19 (6,095-7,072), 1971 May-December 31 (Reel 9)
    - Volume 20 (7,073-9,012), 1972 (Reel 9)
    - Volume 21 (9,013-9,097), 1973 January 1-November 8 (Reel 9)
    - Volume 22 (9,098-10,067), 1973 November 16-1974 March 18 (Reel 9)
    - Volume 23 (10,068-11,023), 1974 March 21-1974 June 20 (Reel 9)
    - Volume 24 (11,024-12,054), 1974 June 24-1975 March 5 (Reel 10)
    - Volume 25 (12,055-13,117), 1975 March 20-1975 June 19 (Reel 10)
    - Volume 26 (13,118-13,220), 1975 July 23-1976 April 23 (Reel 10)
    - Volume 27 (13,221-13,236), 1976 June 2-July 2 (Reel 10)
    - Volume 28 (13,237-13,273), 1976 October 28-1977 March 4 (Reel 10)
    - Volume 29 (13,274-13,291), 1977 March 17-19 (Reel 11)
    - Volume 30 (13,292-13,311), 1977 June 16-July 21 (Reel 11)
    - Volume 31 (13,312-13,324), 1977 September 19-November 4 (Reel 11)
    - Volume 32 (13,325-13,342), 1977 November 17-1978 January 26 (Reel 11)
    - Volume 33 (13,343-13,360), 1978 March 7-1978 May 18 (Reel 11)
    - Volume 34 (13,361-13,384), 1978 June 15-1978 September 21 (Reel 11)
    - Volume 35 (13,385-13,410), 1978 October 4-November 12 (Reel 12)
    - Volume 36 (13,411-13,440), 1978 November 7-1979 March 14 (Reel 12)
    - Volume 37 (13,441-13,472), 1979 March 15-July 16 (Reel 12)
    - Volume 38 (13,473-13,505), 1979 October 31-1980 February 5 (Reel 12)
    - Volume 39 (13,506-13,537), 1980 March 21-July 10 (Reel 12)
    - Volume 40 (13,538-13,580), 1980 October 29-1981 March 20 (Reel 13)
    - Volume 41 (13,581-13,607), 1981 May 7-October 5 (Reel 13)
    - Volume 42 (13,608-13,684), 1981 December 2-1982 April 16 (Reel 13)
    - Volume 43 (13,685-13,767), 1982 June 22-1983 February 15 (Reel 14)
    - Volume 44 (13,768-13,833), 1983 March 7-November 18 (Reel 14)
    - Volume 45 (13,834-13,906), 1984 February 2-October 17 (Reel 14)
    - Volume 46 (13,907-13,980), 1984 November 29-1985 June 16 (Reel 14)
    - Volume 47 (13,981-14,060), 1985 October 15-1986 April 8 (Reel 15)
    - Volume 48 (14,061-14,136), 1986 June 27-November 21 (Reel 15)
    - Volume 49 (14, 102), 1986 November 21 (Reel 15)
    - Volume 50 (14,137-14,219), 1987 January 27-October 6 (Reel 15)
    - Volume 51 (14,220-14,297), 1987 November 14-1988 October 4 (Reel 15)
    - Volume 52 (14,298-14,360), 1988 November 11-1989 June 27 (Reel 16)
    - Volume 53 (14,361-14,400), 1989 June 27-November 21 (Reel 16)
    - Volume 54 (14,401-14,470), 1989 November 21-1990 June 14 (Reel 16)
    - Volume 55 (14,471-14,564), 1990 June 14-November 20 (Reel 16)
    - Volume 56 (14,565-14,650), 1991 February 12-October 18 (Reel 17)
    - Volume 57 (14,651-14,695), 1991 December 12-1992 June 17 (Reel 17)
    - Volume 58 (14,696-14,754), 1992 June 17-December 17 (Reel 17)
    - Volume 59 (14,755-14,784), 1992 December 17-1993 March 3 (Reel 17)
    - Volume 60 (14,785-14,827), 1993 March 3-June 17 (Reel 17)
    - Volume 61 (14,828-14,877), 1993 June 17-December 16 (Reel 18)
    - Volume 62 (14,878-14,917), 1993 December 16-1994 March 8 (Reel 18)
    - Volume 63 (14,918-14,959), 1994 March 8-1994 June 16 (Reel 18)
    - Volume 64 (14,960-15,006), 1994 June 16-October 13 (Reel 18)
    - Volume 65 (15,007-15,039), 1994 December 15-1995 March 9 (Reel 18)
    - Volume 66 (15,040-15,100), 1995 March 9-June 6 (Reel 19)
    - Volume 67 (15,101-15,149), 1995 October 6-December 14 (Reel 19)
    - Volume 68 (15,150-15,167), 1996 March 7 (Reel 19)
    - Volume 69 (15,168-15,203), 1996 June 4 (Reel 19)
    - Volume 70 (15,204-15,230), 1996 October 4 (Reel 19)
    - Volume 71 (15,231-15,283), 1996 December 12-1997 March 6 (Reel 20)
    - Volume 72 (15,284-15,319), 1997 June 3 (Reel 20)
    - Volume 73 (15,320-15,347), 1997 October 10 (Reel 20)
    - Volume 74 (15,348-15,375), 1997 December 17 (Reel 20)